Miscellaneous periodical contributions, 1921-1957 PS3519 .A39
Lilly Library
Miscellaneous periodical contributions
1921-1957
Lilly Library
Jackson, Margaret Weymouth.
PS3519 .A39
207 Items
The items listed are chiefly short stories by Margaret Weymouth Jackson in whole issues of periodicals.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Jackson was born on February 11, 1895, in Eureka Springs, Arkansas, the daughter of George L. Weymouth, 1865-1950, and Martha Stuart (Connell) Weymouth, 1865-l932. In 1897 the family moved to Richill, Missouri, where her father had a printing shop and a daily paper of his own. She graduated from Lake View High School and spent two years at Hillsdale College, Hillsdale, Michigan in 1900. Her father became the editor of Farm Life and moved his family to Spencer, Indiana, where Jackson did editorial work for her father for a year, then took a position as secretary to the Dean of Wilson College in Chambersburg, Pennsylvania. In 1917 she went to Boston to find war-related work, but eventually moved to Chicago to become associate editor of Better Farming. There she met Charles Carter Jackson, l892-l969, and was married on January 10, 1920. That Spring the family settled on a farm in Canada. Her daughter Martha Florence was born on October 7, 1920, and Elizabeth Ann was born on August 6, 1922, but, because of an injury her husband received in the war, farming was impossible and the winters were so severe that they came home again to Spencer, Indiana, where their son Charles Weymouth was born on April 1, 1924. Jackson began writing short articles and poems for farm papers, and in November 1923 the first Katherine stories appeared in Farm Life which ran until December 1925. She wrote novels, short stories, and articles for magazines such as American Magazine, Country Gentleman, Good Housekeeping, Ladies Home Journal, and The Saturday Evening Post. The Jacksons lived for a while in Indianapolis in order to give her children better educational advantages, but returned to Spencer, Indiana, where her husband published a magazine and they had a gift shop. Jackson died on April 4, 1974.
Arrangement
The contributions are arranged by periodical.
Scope and Content Note
The items listed are chiefly short stories by Margaret Weymouth Jackson in whole issues of periodicals including Saturday Evening Post, Ladies Home Journal, Woman's Home Companion, McCall's, Woman's Day, Country Gentleman, Farm Life, American Magazine, and Good Housekeeping.
Related Material
Jackson, M.W. mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
- Short stories and articles in The Saturday Evening Post, 1927-1947
  - Some Flies like Vinegar, vol. 200, no. 19, 5 November 1927; p. 10, ll, 117-119,122, 125, 126. (Box 1)
  - Mattie's Machine, vol. 200, no. 30, 21 January 1928; p. 5, 47, 49. 50. (Box 1)
  - Office Broke, vol. 200, no. 37, 10 March 1928; p. 20, 21, 90, 93-96. (Box 1)
  - Miss Sims Resigns, vol. 200. No. 48, 26 May 1928; p. 16, 17, 114, 117, 119, 120. (Box 1)
  - Monkeyshines, vol. 201. No. 4., 28 July 1928; p. 14, 15, 60, 62, 65. (Box 1)
  - A red-headed Country Girl, vol. 201, no. 38, 23 March 1929; p. 12, 13, 134, 137, 138, 140-142. (Box 1)
  - A Year to Wait, vol. 202, no. 1, 6 July 1929; p. 12, 13. 73, 74, 77, 78. (Box 1)
  - Doctor Lockerbie, vol. 202, no. 4, 27 July 1929; p. 8, 9, 86, 88, 91. (Box 1)
  - Love Comes but Once, vol. 202, no. 13, 28 September 1929; p. 16, 17, 58, 62, 66. (Box 1)
  - The Polished Engine, vol. 202, no. 33, 15 February 1930; p. 6, 7, 107, 109, 110. (Box 1)
  - Driveway, vol. 202, no. 35, 1 March 1930; p. 18, 19, 101, 104, 106, 108. (Box 1)
  - Model Discontinued, vol. 202, no. 37, 15 March 1930; p. 24, 25, 170, 173, 174, 177. (Box 2)
  - Repossessed, vol. 202, no. 40, 5 April 1930; p. 26, 27, 180, 182, 184, 187. (Box 2)
  - Without Recourse, vol. 202, no. 42, 19 April 1930; p. 22, 23, 160, 163, 165. (Box 2)
  - Professional, vol. 203, no. 9, 30 August 1930; p. 8, 9, 44, 46, 48, 52. (Box 2)
  - This Way Please, vol. 203, no. 11, 13 September 1930; p. 26, 27, 90, 92, 96. (Box 2)
  - A Hum in the Llamarado, vol. 203, no. 13, 27 September 1930; p. 20, 21, 89, 91, 94, 97. (Box 2)
  - Business Piano, vol. 203, no. 15, 11 October 1930; p. 20, 21, 90, 92, 95, 99, 102. (Box 2)
  - Mortar and Pestle, vol. 203, no. 43, 25 April 1931; p. 14, 15, 80, 85, 88. (Box 2)
  - Not so New-Fangled, vol. 203, no. 45, 9 May 1931; p. 28, 30, 60, 63, 64, 66, 68. (Box 2)
  - Cash and Carry, vol. 204, no. 19, 7 November 1931; p. 8, 9, 42, 46, 48, 50. (Box 2)
  - Christmas at Rileys, vol. 204, no. 23, 5 December 1931; p. 14, 15, 108, 110, 113. (Box 2)
  - A Matter of Technic, vol. 204, no. 31, 30 January 1932; p. 24, 27, 51, 54, 59. (Box 3)
  - The Cornstalk, vol. 209, no. 12, 19 September 1936; p. 14, 15, 42, 43, 46. (Box 3)
  - A New System, vol. 210. No, 6, 7 August 1937; p. 31, 33, 34, 36. (Box 3)
  - The Daft Mare, vol. 210, no. 17, 23 October 1937; p. 16, 17, 90-92, 94. (Box 3)
  - Abide with Me, vol. 210, no. 49, 4 June 1938; p. 7, 26, 28-30. (Box 3)
  - The Mother of the McIlveys, vol. 210, no. 51, 18 June 1938; p. 7, 70, 71, 73. (Box 3)
  - Some Can't Take It. vol. 211, no. 2, 9 July 1938; p. 7, 68-71. (Box 3)
  - The Bill of Rights. vol. 211, no. 4, 23 July 1938; p. 17, 50, 54, 56. (Box 3)
  - Another Fifteen Years. vol. 211, no. 19, 5 November 1938; p. 16, 17, 53, 54, 56. (Box 3)
  - Many are Called. vol. 212, no. 23, 2 December 1939; p. 12, 13, 72-75. (Box 3)
  - Goon Castle. vol. 212, no. 36, 2 March 1940; p. 20, 21, 76-78, 81. (Box 3)
  - Wish me Luck. vol. 213, no. 27, 4 January 1941; p. 9-11, 68-70, 72. (Box 3)
  - Wish me Luck (part two). vol. 213, no. 28, 11 January 1941; p. 30, 33, 71-76. (Box 3)
  - South Toward Home. vol. 213, no. 42, 19 April 1941; p. 12, 13, 90, 92, 94, 97. (Box 3)
  - The Silk Shirt. vol. 214, no. 32, 7 February 1942; p. 22, 23, 72, 73, 75-77. (Box 3)
  - Selected for Service. vol. 215, no. 16, 17 October 1942; p. 18, 19, 37, 39, 41. (Box 3)
  - So We Don't Know There's a War. vol. 215, no. 46, 15 May 1943; p. 16, 17, 91, 92, 94. (Box 3)
  - Hour of Victory. vol. 218, no. 39, 30 March 1946; p. 16, 75, 78. (Box 3)
  - The Magic Geranium. vol. 220, no. 13, 27 September 1947; p. 22, 119, 120, 122, 124, 126. (Box 3)
- Short stories and articles in Ladies' Home Journal, 1930-1950
  - Pollywog. vol. XLVII, no. 3, March 1930; p. 26, 27, 141, 146. (Box 4)
  - For Barbara. vol. XLVII, no. 9, September 1930; p. 20, 21, 220, 223. (Box 4)
  - Blonde. vol. XLVIII, no. 2, February 1931; p. 6, 7, 44, 46, 48. (Box 4)
  - First Fiddle. vol. XLVIII, no. 12, December 1931; p. 4, 5, 42, 44, 46, 49, 52, 54. (Box 4)
  - First Fiddle (conclusion), vol. XLIX, no. 3, March 1932; p. 54, 88, 91, 92, 94, 96, 97. (Box 4)
  - Mary Edith and the Whited Sepulchers. vol. LI, no. 10, October 1934; p. 16, 17, 52, 54, 56. (Box 4)
  - A Man's Own Money. vol. LI, no. 11, November 1934; p. 18, 19, 89, 91, 95, 98. (Box 4)
  - The Romantic Type. vol. LII, no. 4, April 1935; p. 8, 9, 76, 78, 80, 81, 83. (Box 4)
  - A Mutual Affair. vol. LII, no. 7, July 1935; p. 18, 19, 104-108. (Box 4)
  - Bright as a Christmas Tree, vol. LII, no. 12, December 1935; p. 10, 11, 50, 52, 53, 55. (Box 4)
  - False Spring, vol. LIII, no. 4, April 1936; p. 5-7, 126-128, 130-132. (Box 5)
  - False Spring (part two), vol. LIII, no. 5, May 1936; p. 16, 17, 118, 120-122, 124-129. (Box 5)
  - Mail's Up, vol. LIV, no. 7, July 1937; p. 50, 51, 70, 72, 73. (Box 5)
  - Safety, vol. LV. No. 7, July 1938; p. 14, 15, 51-54. (Box 5)
  - The Breath of Scandal, vol. LVI, no. 1, January 1939; p. 18, 51-54. (Box 5)
  - The Moonlit Cup, vol. LVI, no. 7, July 1939; p. 20, 21, 44-48, 50. (Box 5)
  - The Nest, vol. LVIII, no. 11, November 1941; p. 22, 23, 75-77. (Box 5)
  - One Night, vol. LX, no. 4, April 1943; p. 17, 116, 117, 119, 120. (Box 5)
  - You Need Someone Young, vol. LX, no. 7, July 1943; p. 17, 46, 48, 49. (Box 5)
  - One Day After Another, vol. LX, no. 10, October 1943; p. 36, 37, 152-156. (Box 5)
  - Back Comes the Bride, vol. LXI, no. 2, February 1944; p. 36, 37, 73. (Box 5)
  - Best Man for Milly, vol. LXI, no, 6, June 1944; p. 28, 29, 65, 67-69. (Box 5)
  - The Long Way, vol. LXII, no. 1, January 1945; p. 32, 33, 88-90. (Box 5)
  - Turnabout, vol. LXII, no. 3, March 1945; p. 28, 29, 157, 158, 160, 163. (Box 5)
  - Big Shot, vol. LXII, no. 11, November 1945; p. 40, 41, 172, 173, 175. (Box 6)
  - Time Enough, vol. LXIII, no. 4, April 1946; p. 20, 21, 228, 229, 231, 233. (Box 6)
  - Not Beautiful, vol. LXIII, no. 6, June 1946; p. 20, 21, 198, 199. (Box 6)
  - How America Lives: the Perfectionist Housewife, vol. LXIII, no. 9, September 1946; p. 159-164, 186. (Box 6)
  - Casual Kindness, vol. LXIII, no. 11, November 1946; p. 20, 21, 91, 92. (Box 6)
  - Spring Rain, vol. LXIII, no. 12, December 1946; p. 26, 27, 160, 162. (Box 6)
  - May Day Madness, vol. LXIV, no. 2, February 1947; p. 40, 41, 83-85, 87. (Box 6)
  - How America Lives: On Her Own, vol. LXIV, no. 9, September 1947; p. 195-200, 218, 220-223. (Box 6)
  - The Little Small Young Thing, vol. LXIV, no. 5, May 1949; p. 138, 39, 171-174, 176, 177, 179. (Box 6)
  - How America Lives: Always Home for One More, vol. LXVII, no. 1, January 1950; p. 111-114, 125-127. (Box 6)
- Short stories and articles in Woman's Home Companion, 1928-1942
  - A Clean Cut, vol. LV, no. 10, October 1928; p. 15-17, 71, 72. (Box 6)
  - One Round Trip Ticket, vol. LVI, no. 6, June 1929; p. 7-9, 99. (Box 6)
  - The Compleat Letter-Writer, vol. LVIII, no. 5, May 1931; p. 18, 19, 110, 113, 114. (Box 6)
  - Anything, vol. LVIII, no. 9, September 1931; p. 18, 19, 137, 138. (Box 6)
  - The Season's Greetings, vol. LXI, no. 12, December 1934; p. 19, 20, 77-79, 85. (Box 6)
  - No Nonesense, vol. LXII, no. 2, February 1935; p. 28, 58, 62, 68. (Box 6)
  - Dreams do Come True, vol. LXIII, no. 5, May 1936; p. 25, 26, 94, 96-98. (Box 6)
  - Hit or Miss, vol. LXV, no. 5, May 1938; p. 16, 17, 90, 93, 94, 96. (Box 6)
  - Just Sit Still, vol, LXVI, no. 4., April 1939; p. 24, 25, 32, 38, 42, 44. (Box 6)
  - A Suitable Marriage, vol. LXVI, no. 8, August 1939; p. 24, 25, 84. (Box 6)
  - Different Kinds of Magic, vol. LXVI, no. 9, September 1939; p. 18, 19, 90, 91, 93, 96. (Box 8)
  - If the Shoe Fits, vol. LXVII, no. 11, November 1940; p. 13, 14, 41, 42, 48. (Box 8)
  - It's All so Simple, vol. LXVIII, no. 7, July 1941; p. 18, 19, 65, 66, 73. (Box 8)
  - It's my Turn Now, vol. LXIX, no. 5, May 1942; p. 28, 90, 92, 93, 96-100. (Box 8)
- Short stories and articles in McCall's, 1930-1944
  - Holiday, vol. LVII, no. 7, April 1930; p. 28, 29, 171-173, 176. (Box 8)
  - Candlelight, vol. LVIII, no. 1, October 1930; p. 18, 19, 64, 66, 68. (Box 8)
  - Love Story, vol. LVIII, no. 8, May 1931; p. 11-13, 29, 30. (Box 8)
  - Cup Brimming Over, vol. LXII, no. 12, September 1935; p. 10, 11, 25, 26. (Box 8)
  - Braggart, vol. LXIV, no. 3, December 1936; p. 20, 21, 73, 74, 77. (Box 8)
  - Just to Please Mother, vol. LXVII, no. 1, October 1939; p. 11, 87-91. (Box 8)
  - Youth Passed this Way, vol. LXXI, no. 8, May 1944; p. 11-13, 48, 50, 54, 56, 58, 62, 63. (Box 8)
  - Youth Passed this Way (part two), vol. LXXI, no. 9, June 1944; p. 16, 17, 38, 40, 48, 50, 52, 56, 60, 64. (Box 8)
  - Youth Passed this Way (part three), vol. LXXI, no. 10, July 1944; p. 24, 25, 50, 54-56, 58, 60, 61. (Box 8)
- Short stories and articles in Woman's Day, 1939-1952
  - The Greatest Lady, vol. 2, no. 7, April 1939; p. 12, 13, 41-43. (Box 9)
  - The 'Hilltown Crier' vol. 3. No. 7, April 1940; p. 11-13, 38, 39, 42-46, 50, 57, 59. (Box 9)
  - The 'Hilltown Crier' (part two), vol. 3, no. 8, May 1940; p. 30, 31, 32, 42, 43, 50-56. (Box 9)
  - The 'Hilltown Crier' (part three), vol. 3, no. 9, June 1940; p. 28, 29, 38, 39, 42, 43, 46, 47. (Box 9)
  - The 'Hilltown Crier' (part four) vol. 3, no. 10, July 1940; p. 23-27, 56-59. (Box 9)
  - The 'Hilltown Crier' (conclusion) vol. 3, no. 11, August 1940; p. 30-32, 42-46. (Box 9)
  - This is my Wife, vol. 4, no. 4, January 1941; p. 26-28, 48-50. (Box 9)
  - Good-by, true love, vol. 11, no. 5, February 1948; p. 28, 29, 54, 58, 60, 61, 83. (Box 9)
  - Killer's Conscience, vol. 15, no. 6, March 1952; p. 72, 73, 165-174. (Box 9)
  - The Ceramic Grasshopper, vol. 16, no. 1, October 1952; p. 122-124, 126-128, 130, 131, 156. (Box 9)
- Short stories and articles in Country Gentleman, 1929-1950
  - Mustard Flower, vol. XCIV, no. 7, July 1929; p. 24, 78. (Box 10)
  - Not in the Curriculum, vol. XCV, no. 5, May 1930; p. 6, 7, 100, 102, 105, 107. (Box 10)
  - Great Moments, vol. CI, no. 3, March 1931; p. 28, 29, 135-139. (Box 10)
  - The Princess, vol. CI, no. 6, June 1931; p. 10, 11, 56, 57. (Box 10)
  - A New Road for Jane, vol. CIV, no. 4, April 1934; p. 8, 9, 46, 48, 50. (Box 10)
  - The Refined Miss Heatherington, vol, CV, no. 3, March 1935; p. 16, 17, 76-79. (Box 10)
  - Gentle People, vol. CV, no. 7, July 1935; p. 5-7, 62-64. (Box 10)
  - The Wishing Sock, vol. CVI, no. 2, February 1936; p. 14, 15, 37-41. (Box 10)
  - The Goldfish Bowl, vol. CVI, no. 10, October 1936; p. 10, 11, 88-91. (Box 10)
  - The Tuft of Hair, vol. CVII, no. 10, October 1937; p. 10, 11, 27, 28, 30-32, 34-36. (Box 10)
  - The Tuft of Hair (part two), vol. CVII, no. 11, November 1937; p. 16, 17, 27, 28, 30, 32, 34, 36, 37. (Box 10)
  - The Tuft of Hair (conclusion), vol. CVII, no. 12, December 1937; p. 18, 19, 26, 28, 29, 32,34, 36, 37, 40. (Box 10)
  - Do You Remember? Vol. CVIII, no. 1, January 1938; p. 18, 19, 60-62. (Box 10)
  - Shark's Teeth, vol. CVIII, no. 5, May 1938; p. 18, 19, 74-77. (Box 10)
  - Sixth Christmas, vol. CVIII, no. 12, December 1938; p. 52, 59, 60. (Box 10)
  - The Lucky Break, vol. CIX, no. 4, April 1939; p. 10, 11, 38, 41, 42, 44. (Box 11)
  - Music Lesson, vol. CIX, no. 8, August 1939; p. 14, 15, 59-61. (Box 11)
  - House for Rent, vol. CX, no. 3, March 1940; p. 10, 11, 39-42. (Box 11)
  - Has your School Gone Fancy? Vol. CX, no. 12, December 1940; p. 7, 8, 54. (Box 11)
  - Captive Audience, vol. CXI, no. 1, January 1941; p. 19, 44, 45. (Box 11)
  - The Fighting Heart, vol. CXII, no. 3, March 1942; p. 86. (Box 11)
  - The Ashers of Indiana, vol. CXVii, no. 5, May 1947; p. 16, 17, 82, 85-87. (Box 11)
  - The Elders Rent in Illinois, vol. CXVII, no. 11, November 1947; p. 22, 23, 84-86, 88-92. (Box 11)
  - Ohio Bride and Groom, vol. CXVIII, no. 11, November 1948; p. 28, 29, 183-188. (Box 11)
  - Day of the Big Game, vol. CXX, no. 2, February 1950; p. 35, 159-165. (Box 11)
  - Carolina Conservationist, vol. CXX, no. 7, July 1950; p. 24, 25, 94-98. (Box 11)
  - Farm Christmas, vol. CXX, no. 12, December 1950; p. 28, 29, 58, 60-63. (Box 11)
- Short stories and articles in Farm Life, 1921-1929
  - Farm Life, vol. XL, no. 12, Seen from my Kitchen Door, December 1921; p. 32. (Box 11)
  - Farm Life, vol. XLI, no. 3-12, 1922; Bound volume. (Box 11)
    Scope and Contents
    Seen from my Kitchen Door, no. 3, March 1922, p. 46, 47.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 4, April 1922, p. 42, 43.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 5, May 1922, p. 34.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 6, June 1922, p. 32.33.
    Seen from My Kitchen Door, no. 7, July 1922, p. 31.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 8, August 1922, p. 30, 31.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 9. September 1922, p. 46, 47.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 10, October 1922, p. 60, 61.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 11, November 1922, p. 60, 61.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 12, December 1922, p. 47, 48.
  - Farm Life, vol. XLII, no. 1-12, 1923; Bound volume. (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, no. 1, January 1923, p. 59.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 3, March 1923, p. 62, 63.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 4, April 1923, p. 52, 53.
    Dorcas Leaves Home, no. 4, April 1923, p. 12, 37, 38.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 5, May 1923, p. 32, 33.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 6. June 1923, p. 26, 27.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 7, July 1923, p. 19.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 8, August 1923, p. 28, 29.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 9, September 1923, p. 36, 37.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 10, October 1923, p. 44, 45.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 11, November 1923, p. 56, 57.
    Katherine and the Storm, no. 11, November 1923, p. 8, 9, 51.
    My Kitchen Door, no. 12, December 1923, p. 38, 39.
    Katherine's stove, no. 12, December 1923, p. 8, 9, 41.
  - Farm Life, vol. XLIII, no. 3, March 1924 (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, p. 60, 61.
    Katherine and the Lord's house, p. 8, 9, 57, 58
  - Farm Life, vol. XLIII, no. 10, October 1924 (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, p. 50, 51.
    John and Effie, p. 9, 44, 45
  - Farm Life, vol. XLIV, no. 9, September 1925 (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, p. 43-45.
    Katherine has some queer neighbors, p. 8, 9, 46, 48, 52.
  - Farm Life, vol. XLIV, no. 10, October 1925 (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, p. 52.
    When Ma Higbee left home, p. 8, 9, 60.
  - Farm Life, vol. XLIV, no. 12, December 1925 (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, p. 46.
    The Herald Angels, p. 8, 9, 42.
  - Farm Life, vol. XLV, no. 1, January 1926 (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, p. 54, 55.
    Elizabeth Whittaker, p. 8, 9, 30, 44-49.
  - Farm Life, vol. XLV, no. 2, February 1926 (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, p. 66
    Elizabeth Whittaker, p. 8, 9, 53-57, 63.
  - Farm Life, vol. XLV, no. 3, March 1926 (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, p. 52, 53.
    Elizabeth Whittaker, p. 8, 9, 44-47, 50, 51.
  - Farm Life, vol. XLV, no. 10, October 1926 (Box 12)
    Elizabeth Whittaker, p. 8, 9, 28, 36, 37.
  - Farm Life, vol. XLV, no. 11., November 1926 (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, p. 58
    Elizabeth Whittaker, p. 8, 9, 44, 56.
  - Farm Life, XLVIII, no. 7, July 1929 (Box 12)
    My Kitchen Door, p. 24
    The Old Bridge, p. 8, 9, 24.
- Short stories and articles in The American Magazine, 1933-1949
  - Shall we get Rid of the Family? Vol. CXVI, no. 1, July 1933; p. 18, 19, 108-111. (Box 12)
  - Quarry, vol. CXVIII. No. 3, September 1934; p. 78-8-, 136-139. (Box 12)
  - Henpecked Maid, vol. CXXIII, no. 5, May 1937; p. 52-55, 86, 89, 91, 92, 94, 95. (Box 12)
  - Family Affair, vol. CXXIII, no. 6, June 1937; p. 44, 45, 110-114, 117. (Box 12)
  - Thief in the Night, vol. CXXIV, no. 1, July 1937; p. 46-49, 98-100. (Box 12)
  - Fair Enough, vol. CXXIV, no. 4, October 1937; p. 38-41, 125-128. (Box 12)
  - Money will Burn, vol. CXXV, no. 1, January 1938; p. 36-39, 94-96. (Box 12)
  - The Best of Everything, vol. CXXXIV, no. 5, November 1942; p. 18-21, 74-81. (Box 12)
  - The Best of Everything (conclusion), vol. CXXXIV, no. 6, December 1942; p. 152-158. (Box 12)
  - A Sword of Steel, vol. CXXXV, no. 3, March 1943; p. 48, 49, 83-86. (Box 12)
  - End of a Dream, vol. CXLVI, no. 4., October 1948; p. 32, 33, 81, 82, 84, 86-88, 91. (Box 12)
  - One More Journey, vol. CXLVIII, no. 6, December 1949; p. 22, 23, 90, 92-95. (Box 12)
- Short stories and articles in Good Housekeeping, 1925-1941
  - The Stars that Shine, vol. LXXXI, no. 5, November 1925; p. 74-77, 217. (Box 14)
  - The Red Glass Bowl, vol. xx, no. 4, December 1931; p. 34-37, 181-184. (Box 14)
  - Marriage as it Ought To Be, vol. XCVI, no. 6, June 1933; p. 44, 45, 165-168. (Box 14)
  - Anthony Scarlet's Christmas Eve, vol. 101, no. 6, December 1935; p. 42-45, 145-147. (Box 14)
  - For I Am Sick of Love, vol. III, no. 6, December 1940; p. 24, 25, 64, 66, 68. (Box 14)
  - Eighteen All Over, vol. 112, no. 4, April 1941; p. 24, 25, 91-97. (Box 14)
  - The Day I First Saw You, vol. 113, no. 2, August 1941; p. 44, 45, 139-143. (Box 14)
- Miscellaneous material by Margaret Weymouth Jackson, 1921-1957
  Periodicals include:
  The Baguio Reporter
  Collier's
  Cosmopolitan
  Country Home Magazine
  Everywoman
  The Farmer's Wife
  Life Story Magazine
  Home Life
  This Week Magazine (The Indianapolis Star)
  This Week Magazine (The New York Herald Tribune)
  Modern Home
  Mother
  My Home
  Pictorial Review
  The Storyteller
  Wife and Home
  Woman
  Woman's Fair
  Woman's Journal
  Woman's Pictorial
  Woman's Weekly
  Young People
  Good Housekeeping, the Star Weekly
  Great Sports Stories
  - Shall we get rid of the Family, in the Baguio Reporter, January 1946; p. 9, 17. (Box 15)
  - The Sticking Point, in Collier's, vol. 107, no. 9, 1 March 1941; p. 16, 39, 40, 42, 43. (Box 15)
  - Never Forget Spring. In Cosmopolitan, vol. 116, no. 4, February 1944; p. 69-72, 75, 76, 78, 80, 82, 85, 86, 88, 90, 95, 96, 98, 100, 102, 105, 106. (Box 15)
  - The Stepmother. In Cosmopolitan, vol. 124, no. 1, January 1948; p. 38, 39, 131-133. (Box 15)
  - Decoration Day. In the Country Home Magazine, vol. 61, no. 5, May 1937; p. 16, 17, 46, 47, 49. (Box 15)
  - Hill of Dreams. In the Country Home Magazine, vol. 62, no. 7, July 1938; p. 8, 9. (Box 15)
  - Sixth Christmas. In Everywoman, December 1940; p. 8-10. (Box 15)
  - The Tongue is a Little member. In The Farmer's Wife, vol. 39, no. 4., April 1936; p. 5, 6, 33, 37, 39. (Box 15)
  - The Perfectionist Housewife. In Home Life, vol. 1, no. 2, February 1947; p. 18-21. (Box 15)
  - The Young of Heart. In Life Story Magazine, vol. 11, no. 64, February 1945; p. 30-33, 54. (Box 15)
  - If She Wants Rhythm. In This Week Magazine (Indianapolis Sunday Star), 30 October 1938; p. 8, 9, 14. (Box 15)
  - Christmas Crisis. In This Week Magazine (Indianapolis Sunday Star), 25 December 1938; p. 3, 12, 13. (Box 15)
  - If She Wants Rhythm. In This Week Magazine (New York Herald Tribune), 30 October 1938; p. 6, 7, 26. (Box 15)
  - Not So New-Fangled. In Modern Home, no. 36, September 1931; p. 18-22, 66, 69, 70, 72-75. (Box 15)
  - The Most Important Person, In Mother, vol. 3, no. 27, December 1938; p. 22-25, 106, 107. (Box 15)
  - Blonde. In My Home, January 1931; p. 14-18, 60, 63, 64. (Box 15)
  - That's My Private Sorrow. In Pictorial Review Combined with Delineator, vol. 38, no. 11, August 1937; p. 20, 21, 50, 54, 57. (Box 15)
  - Escape. In The Storyteller, vol. LVII, no. 341, August 1935; p. 630-636. (Box 15)
  - Men Are Hard to Please. In Wife and Home, vol. XXII, no. 130, July 1940; p. 21, 22, 60, 61. (Box 16)
  - Different Kinds of Magic. In Woman, vol. 5, no. 127, 4 November 1939; p. 7, 8, 10, 38, 41. (Box 16)
  - Mystery of Love. In Woman, vol. 17, no. 426, 28 July 1945; p. 5-8. (Box 16)
  - Safety. In Woman's Fair, vol. 5, no. 53, September 1938; p. 36-38, 57, 58. (Box 16)
  - This is My Love. In Woman's Journal, vol. XXXVI, no. 212, June 1945; p. 8, 9, 49, 50. (Box 16)
  - For Love of Him. In Woman's Pictorial, vol. 28, no. 29, 29 December 1934; p. 4-7. (Box 16)
  - Not Enough Love. In Woman's Pictorial, vol. 32, no. 820, 26 September 1936; p. 14-17, 48, 51. (Box 16)
  - Something's Sure to Happen. In Woman's Pictorial, vol. 36, no. 912, 2 July 1938; p. 10-13. (Box 16)
  - Where the Heart belongs. In Woman's Pictorial, vol. 37, no. 947, 4 March 1939; p. 28-30, 49, 50. (Box 16)
  - Spring Afternoon. In Woman's Weekly, vol. XLV, no. 1169, 31 March 1934; p. 515-518, 538-540. (Box 16)
  - The Season's Greetings. In Woman's Weekly, vol. XLVI, no. 1208, 29 December 1934; p. 1127, 1130, 1132. (Box 16)
  - The Gold-Fish Bowl. In Woman's Weekly, vol. L, no. 1308, 28 November 1936; p. 1051-1054, 1056, 1087, 1088, 1091, 1092. (Box 16)
  - Dry Summer. In Woman's Weekly, vol. LIV, no. 1399, 27 August 1938; p. 379-382, 384, 406-408, 411. (Box 16)
  - Do You Remember? In Woman's Weekly, vol. LIV, no. 1414, 10 December 1938; p. 1213, 1216, 1244, 1245, 1247, 1248, 1251. (Box 16)
  - Each Little Sun. In Woman's Weekly, vol. LXVIII, no. 1770, 6 October 1945; p. 367-370. (Box 16)
  - The Perfectionist Housewife. In Young People, vol. 66, no. 41, 13 October 1944; p. 2, 3, 7. (Box 16)
  - The Red Glass Bowl. Excerpt from Good Housekeeping, December 1931; p. 58-61, 167-171. (Box 16)
  - Eldest Daughter. Excerpt from Good Housekeeping, December 1938; p. 46, 47, 84-89. (Box 16)